# **NEIL JOSEPH S. BESTIL**

#### COMPUTER ENGINEER

Makani Bldg., Al Muraqqabat, Deira, Dubai, UAE

+971 52 246 5535



I am a Computer Engineering graduate with 12 years of experience in the IT business industry. Over the course of my career, I have worked as a Full-Stack Developer for six years, specializing in different platforms. Additionally, I have served as a Technical Lead, demonstrating leadership in project management, server hosting management, and the seamless integration of applications through REST APIs.

In pursuit of continuous enhancement in my role as a Front-end Developer, I have undertaken deliberate measures to refine my design proficiency by completing my studies as a graphic designer.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

- Adequate knowledge and skills with computer systems
- Excellent analytical and technical skills
- Proficient in oral and written english communication skills

### Software Developer

- Experienced in System Development Life Cycle (SDLC) work environment
- System and Data Analyst
- Experienced in Data and Quality Assurance processing
- Great knowledge in Object-Oriented Programming and MVC (Model View Control) architecture
- Project Management
  - Good documentation skills
  - Client engagement/assistance
  - Monitoring email, request and data to ensure quick response
  - Multi-tasking
  - Critical thinking

- A team player with good leadership skills
- Flexible and fast learner
- Creative and with good skills in arts and design
- Full-Stack Developer
  - Intermediate web designing skills
  - Experienced in different up-to date front-end framework platforms
  - Experienced in different up-to date back-end framework platforms
  - Figma
  - GIMP/Adobe Photoshop
  - CorelDraw/Adobe Illustrator

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### AVIDHILDA

The Prism, Business Bay, Dubai, UAE

July 2023 - Present

#### Technical Lead

Supervises the technical dimensions of a software team, making strategic architectural and design decisions, offering guidance to team members on technical matters, and overseeing system modifications. The projects we have undertaken include e-commerce, content management systems (CMS), and booking systems.

Technical Skills: Laravel, SQL, ReactJS, Tailwind, REST APIs, Cpanel, Bitbucket, Sourcetree, Postman

#### APPSPRO

Park Lane Tower, Business Bay, Dubai, UAE December 2019 - June 2023

# Oracle Cloud Technical Consultant

Working as a Full-Stack Developer. Mainly on Oracle Integration Cloud which develop custom web application that integrates with Oracle Cloud (SaaS) Apps. Core duties are as follows:

- Programming web application using Angular, Oracle Jet frameworks in front-end.
- Programming REST web services and integrates application to Oracle Cloud (SaaS) in back-end.
- Provides solutions and support for customers related to Oracle Integration Cloud REST/SOAP APIs.
- QA Teste

Technical Skills: JAVA, SQL, Angular, Oracle Jet, REST/SOAP APIs, Postman/SoapUI, Sourcetree, Oracle WebLogic Server

## **GIS INTERNATIONAL**

Churchill Tower, Business Bay, Dubai, UAE December 2018 - December 2019

#### Senior Web Developer

Working as a Full-Stack web developer that caters the client's specification requirements. List of projects I worked on:

- POS System Developing E-commerce/Online booking website.
- Management System Developing management web application (e.g. CMS, HCM)

Technical Skills: Laravel, SQL, Bootstrap, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, REST APIs, Cpanel, Bitbucket, Sourcetree, Postman

#### **ALLIANCE SOFTWARE INC.**

Cebu City, Cebu, Philippines 6000 January 2018 - May 2018

#### Web Developer

Working as support web developer of an E-Commerce web app with POS system integration for fast food chain. Core duties are as follows:

- Back-end programmer
- QA Tester
- Support

Technical Skills: Codelgniter, SQL, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, Bitbucket, Sourcetree, Cpanel

#### **DYNATA CEBU**

Lapu-lapu City, Cebu, Philippines 6015 December 2011 - January 2018

## Survey Programmer

Working as Survey Programmer in one of the leading programming and hosting provider in the market research industry. Core duties are as follows:

- Programming web survey with the latest design techniques across all modes and mobile compatibility
- Extensive survey testing and data verification for quality control process
- Ensuring respondent's engagement and optimal in-field performance by checking mobile friendly design and compatibility across multiple technology platforms and display issues
- Processing data which includes data cleansing, delivery of raw data, tables, and charts for reporting
- System and Data analyst, providing clients with efficiency, insights, and strategic recommendation for their business

Technical Skills: PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Confirmit, AWS Cloud

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **FILIPINO INSTITURE ACADEMY**

Dubai, UAE November 2022 - May 2023

#### Graphic Designer Diploma

For my final project, I established a company and executed graphic design projects within its scope. These included the creation of letterhead, brochure, logo, business card, envelope, magazine cover, and advertisement poster.

#### **UNIVERSITY OF SAN CARLOS**

Cebu City, Cebu, Philippines 6000 2006 - 2011

### Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineer (Software Engineering Major)

My thesis focused on the integration across multiple platforms; mobile, desktop, and web for a catering business. This encompassed the development of an e-commerce platform, content management system (CMS), and inventory system, utilizing Java and Bootstrap.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **Programming**

PHP, Java, MySql, SqlLite, Oracle SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, ReactJS, Angular, OracleJet, Laravel, Codelgniter

# Web/Application Server

Wamp/Xamp, Cpanel, Oracle Weblogic Server, Windows Server

## Platforms

Visual Studio Code, Oracle JDeveloper, Oracle SQLDeveloper, Confirmit, AWS Cloud, Postman/SoapUI, GIT - Sourcetree, Bitbucket

## **RELEVANT SKILLS**

#### Computer

Microsoft Office 365, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Figma, GIMP

#### Languages

English, Filipino (Native)

## **REFERENCES**

References available on request.